this brings us to the end of our
introductory session
covering the basics of health insurance
this section details some of the
information you'll need to move through
the balance of the course
such as terminology and basic health
insurance policy information
we discuss important definitions that
are used in health and disability
contracts
which brought us to policy types use of
both group
and individual policies and the
principal types of losses and benefits
we went on to cover limited coverage
contracts
managed care required legal notices
and how premiums are calculated
the lesson continued with a look at how
the underwriting of a risk is processed
sources of underwriting information risk
classifications
and options available to your
underwriter we concluded the lesson with
an in-depth discussion of producer
responsibilities
consideration in replacing existing
contracts
creditable coverage documentation
pre-existing condition concerns
and required notifications as a reminder
make sure to obtain a copy of your
state's content outlines
they'll contain information regarding
how many questions are asked
on the state exam for each portion of
the test you'll find out that
certain areas of your exam are tested
more heavily than others
and it's always a good idea to spend
most of your study time in those areas
that can
most impact your test score as we go
through the remainder of this course
the next sections will expand on all the
information we've covered here in much
greater detail
congratulations on a great beginning to
your health insurance training
and we'll see you in the next lesson